A Guide to the Records the State Archivist of the Library of Virginia, 1930-1990
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Records of the State Archivist of the Library of Virginia, 1930-1990
The Library of Virginia
27952
X cubic feet (XX Boxes)
State Archivist
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Accession 52180 transferred from the Office of the State Archivist on March 14, 1973.
Historical Information
XX
Scope and Content
XX
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I. William Barrow Restoration Lab records, 2014-2017
Contents List
- Correspondence and subject files, 1930-1990., Extent: X boxes. (Box X-X)
  XX
  - William Barrow Restoration Lab records, X-X.
    Includes: Budget materials, 1943-1979; Correspondence, 1934-1977; Restoration Procedures, 1939-1972, in numerical/chronological order, which document procedures performed by the restoration lab and Restoration Projects, 1970-1977, which include procedure forms grouped by locality.
    Arranged alphabetically.
    - Budget (Gov. Off.), 1943-1944. (Box 6)
    - Budget (Library), 1943-1944. (Box 6)
    - Budget (Gov. Off.), 1944-1945. (Box 6)
    - Budget (Library), 1944-1945. (Box 6)
    - Budget (Gov. Off.), 1945-1946. (Box 6)
    - Budget (Library), 1945-1946. (Box 6)
    - Budget (Gov. Off.), 1946-1947. (Box 6)
    - Budget (Library), 1946-1947. (Box 6)
    - Budget (Gov. Off.), 1947-1948. (Box 6)
    - Budget (Library), 1947-1948. (Box 6)
    - Budget (Gov. Off.), 1948-1949. (Box 6)
    - Budget (Library), 1948-1949. (Box 6)
    - Budget (Gov. Off.), 1949-1950. (Box 6)
    - Budget (Library), 1949-1950. (Box 6)
    - Budget, 1950-1951. (Box 7)
    - Budget, 1951-1952. (Box 7)
    - Budget, 1952-1953. (Box 7)
    - Budget, 1953-1954. (Box 7)
    - Budget, 1954-1955. (Box 7)
    - Budget, 1955-1956. (Box 7)
    - Budget, 1956-1957. (Box 7)
    - Budget, 1957-1958. (Box 7)
    - Budget, 1958-1959. (Box 7)
    - Budget, 1959-1960. (Box 7)
    - Budget, 1960-1961. (Box 7)
    - Budget, 1961-1962. (Box 8)
    - Budget, 1962-1963. (Box 8)
    - Budget, 1963-1964. (Box 8)
    - Budget, 1964-1965. (Box 8)
    - Budget, 1965-1966. (Box 8)
    - Budget, 1966-1967. (Box 8)
    - Budget, 1967-1968. (Box 8)
    - Budget, 1968-1969. (Box 8)
    - Budget, 1969-1970. (Box 8)
    - Budget, 1970-1971. (Box 9)
    - Budget, 1971-1972. (Box 9)
    - Budget, 1972-1973. (Box 3)
    - Budget, 1975-1976. (Box 3)
    - Budget, 1976-1977. (Box 3)
    - Budget, 1977-1978. (Box 3)
    - Budget, 1978-1979. (Box 3)
    - Budget - Other than state appropriations, 1943-1945. (Box 9)
    - Correspondence, 1934-1971. (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1967. (Box 5)
    - Correspondence, 1970-1975. (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1971-1977. (Box 1)
    - Cost estimates, undated. (Box 1)
    - Dobbs Brothers, undated. (Box 1)
    - Expenses and equipment, 1953-1966. (Box 5)
    - Expenses and equipment, 1960-1968. (Box 5)
    - Expenses and equipment, 1939-1967. (Box 5)
    - Expenses and equ, 19. (Box 4)
    - Federal court records, 1952-1968. (Box 9)
    - Material to be restored, 1960. (Box 1)
    - Orders, 1979-1982. (Box 1)
    - Prices - Barrow Publications, 1939-1978. (Box 3)
    - Projects, 1924-1939. (Box 1)
    - Rent, 1942-1967. (Box 5)
    - Restoration Procedures (No. 1-200), 1939-1942. (Box 9)
    - Restoration Procedures (No. 201-400), 1941-1942. (Box 9)
    - Restoration Procedures (No. 401-600), 1942-1943. (Box 10)
    - Restoration Procedures (No. 601-800), 1942-1944. (Box 10)
    - Restoration Procedures (No. 801-1000), 1944-1945. (Box 10)
    - Restoration Procedures (No. 1001-1199), 1945-1951. (Box 10)
    - Restoration Procedures (No. 1200-1277), 1950-1954. (Box 11)
    - Restoration Procedures, 1954-1958. (Box 11)
    - Restoration Procedures, 1958-1962. (Box 11)
    - Restoration Procedures, 1962-1965. (Box 11)
    - Restoration Procedures, 1965-1972. (Box 11)
    - Restoration Projects: Accomac, 1970-1977. (Box 1)
    - Restoration Projects: Alexandria, 1970-1977. (Box 1)
    - Restoration Projects: Amelia, 1970-1977. (Box 1)
    - Restoration Projects: Augusta, 1970-1977. (Box 1)
    - Restoration Projects: Botetourt, 1970-1977. (Box 1a)
    - Restoration Projects: Brunswick, 1970-1977. (Box 1a)
    - Restoration Projects: Caroline, 1970-1977. (Box 1a)
    - Restoration Projects: Culpeper, 1970-1977. (Box 1a)
    - Restoration Projects: Cumberland, 1970-1977. (Box 1a)
    - Restoration Projects: Dinwiddie, 1970-1977. (Box 1a)
    - Restoration Projects: Elizabeth City, 1970-1977. (Box 1a)
    - Restoration Projects: Essex, 1970-1977. (Box 1a)
    - Restoration Projects: Frederick, 1970-1977. (Box 1a)
    - Restoration Projects: Goochland, 1970-1977. (Box 1a)
    - Restoration Projects: Halifax, 1970-1977. (Box 1a)
    - Restoration Projects: Henrico, 1970-1977. (Box 1a)
    - Restoration Projects: Henry, 1970-1977. (Box 1a)
    - Restoration Projects: Isle of Wight, 1970-1977. (Box 1a)
    - Restoration Projects: King George, 1970-1977. (Box 2)
    - Restoration Projects: Lancaster, 1970-1977. (Box 1a)
    - Restoration Projects: Loudoun, 1970-1977. (Box 1a)
    - Restoration Projects: Louisa, 1970-1977. (Box 1a)
    - Restoration Projects: Mecklenburg, 1970-1977. (Box 1a)
    - Restoration Projects: Montgomery, 1970-1977. (Box 1a)
    - Restoration Projects: Norfolk Co., 1970-1977. (Box 2)
    - Restoration Projects: Orange, 1970-1977. (Box 2)
    - Restoration Projects: Prince Edward, 1970-1977. (Box 2)
    - Restoration Projects: Prince William, 1970-1977. (Box 2)
    - Restoration Projects: Rappahannock, 1970-1977. (Box 2)
    - Restoration Projects: Richmond City, 1970-1977. (Box 2)
    - Restoration Projects: Richmond Co., 1970-1977. (Box 2)
    - Restoration Projects: Rockingham, 1970-1977. (Box 2)
    - Restoration Projects: Russell, 1970-1977. (Box 2)
    - Restoration Projects: Shenandoah, 1970-1977. (Box 2)
    - Restoration Projects: Southampton, 1970-1977. (Box 2)
    - Restoration Projects: Spotsylvania, 1970-1977. (Box 2)
    - Restoration Projects: Stafford, 1970-1977. (Box 2)
    - Restoration Projects: Surry, 1970-1977. (Box 2)
    - Restoration Projects: Sussex, 1970-1977. (Box 2)
    - Restoration Projects: Westmoreland, 1970-1977. (Box 2)
    - Restoration Projects: Wythe, 1970-1977. (Box 2)
    - Restoration Projects: York, 1970-1977. (Box 2)
    - Restoration Projects: State records, 1970-1977. (Box 2)
    - Restoration Projects: State, Local and Personal, 1970-1977. (Box 2)
    - Testing, 1961-1974. (Box 3)
    - Tonken, Mrs. Maurice B., 1959-1975. (Box 3)
  - Internal operations, X-X.
    Includes: Records related to internal operations.
    - Cataloging, 1940-1951. (Box 3a)
    - Correspondence - Letters of recommendation and resignation, 1942-1966. (Box 3a)
    - Equipment and furniture, 1939-1966. (Box 3a)
    - Equipment inventories, 1955-1966. (Box 3a)
    - Expenses and equipment, 1965-1967. (Box 4)
    - Expenses and equipment - Binding (Epps and Snider), 1961-1966. (Box 4)
    - Expenses and equipment - Binding (McCleary), 1961-1968. (Box 4)
    - Expenses and equipment - Binding (Ossman), 1967-1968. (Box 4)
    - Expenses and equipment - Catalogs and price lists, undated. (Box 4)
    - Expenses and equipment - Equipment and furniture, 1960-1968. (Box 4)
    - Expenses and equipment - Folders and binders, 1959-1968. (Box 4)
    - Expenses and equipment - Fumigation, 1939-1957. (Box 4)
    - Folders and boxes, 1949-1969. (Box 3a)
    - Fumigator, 1948-1955. (Box 3a)
    - General, 1940-1961. (Box 3a)
    - Order forms, 1969-1972. (Box 15-16)
  - Internal operations, X-X.
    - Cataloging, 1940-1951. (Box 3a)
    - Permalife Xerox paper, 1966. (Box 3a)
    - Photographic equipment, 1939-1960. (Box 3a)
    - Photographic Laboratory - Budget and operation costs, 1964-1970. (Box 12)
    - Photographic Laboratory - Equipment, 1939-1940. (Box 12)
    - Photographic Laboratory - Equipment inventory, 1952, 1961, 1965. (Box 12)
    - Photographic Laboratory - Equipment - Microfilm camera and reader, 1951-1968. (Box 12)
    - Photographic Laboratory - Equipment - Microfilm file cabinets, 1948-1963. (Box 12)
    - Photographic Laboratory - Equipment - Microfilm filmsort, 1959. (Box 12)
    - Photographic Laboratory - Equipment - Microfilm, 1940-1968. (Box 13)
    - Photographic Laboratory - Microfilm - Correspondence, 1935-1955. (Box 13)
    - Photographic Laboratory - Microfilm - Given to Mr. Barrow for tests, 1958. (Box 13)
    - Photographic Laboratory - Microfilm - Legal status, 1947-1953. (Box 13)
    - Photographic Laboratory - Microfilm - Micro-Photo, Inc., 1951-1960. (Box 13)
    - Photographic Laboratory - Microfilm - Miscellaneous, 1941-1954. (Box 15)
    - Photographic Laboratory - Microfilm - Newspaper microfilming project, 1949-1957. (Box 14)
    - Photographic Laboratory - Microfilm - Notes, undated. (Box 14)
    - Photographic Laboratory - Microfilm - Oscar Fisher, 19. (Box 13)
    - Photographic Laboratory - Microfilm - Prices, 1960. (Box 14)
    - Photographic Laboratory - Microfilm - Record of film, 1942-1954. (Box 14)
    - Photographic Laboratory - Microfilm - Recordak, 1940-1964. (Box 14)
    - Photographic Laboratory - Microfilm - Remington Rand, undated. (Box 14)
    - Photographic Laboratory - Microfilm - Tests, 1943-1957. (Box 14)
    - Photographic Laboratory - Microfilm - Union List of Microfilm, 1953-1955. (Box 14)
    - Photographic Laboratory - Microfilm - University Microfilm, 1946-1957. (Box 15)
    - Photostat Corporation, 1940-1959. (Box 15)
    - Polices and procedures, 1941-1968. (Box 3a)
    - Policies and procedures - Microfilm and photocopying, 1940-1969. (Box 3a)
    - Publication of indexes, 1959. (Box 3a)
    - Publicity, 1940-1956. (Box 3a)
    - Publicity, 1940-1951. (Box 3a)
    - Salary scales, 1942-1963. (Box 3a)
    - Xerography - Micro-Print, Inc., 1959-1964. (Box 15)
  - Subject fles, X-X.
    Includes: XX.
    - Alexandria Historical and Preservation Commission, 1964-1965. (Box 18)
    - American Antiquarian Society, 1957-1967. (Box 18)
    - American Antiquarian Society - Early American Imprints Project, 1957. (Box 18)
    - Architectural Drawing in Virginia since 1819 - Exhibit at UVA and Virginia Museum, 1969. (Box 18)
    - Archives of American Art, 1963-1964. (Box 18)
    - Article - Municipal Records, 1947. (Box 18)
    - Association of Southeaster Research Libraries, undated. (Box 18)
    - Barrow, W. J., 1939-1967. (Box 18)
    - Book reviews and articles, 1941-1967. (Box 18)
    - Branch and Co., 1955-1956. (Box 18)
    - Certification of Teacher Service, 1962-1968. (Box 18)
    - Church Records - Episcopal, 1922-1969. (Box 18)
    - Church Records - Episcopal - Diocese of Southern Virginia (microfilming project), 1961. (Box 18)
    - Church Records - Episcopal - Diocese of Southwestern Virginia (Cocke), 19. (Box 19)
    - Church Records - Episcopal - William H. Seiler, 1959. (Box 18)
    - Church Records - Projects, 1935-1941. (Box 18)
    - Church Records - United Brethren, 1967. (Box 18)
    - Civil War Centennial - Correspondence, 1958-1959. (Box 19)
    - Civil War Centennial - Correspondence, 1960-1963. (Box 19)
    - Civil War Centennial - Publications, 1959-1962. (Box 19)
    - Colonial Williamsburg, 1941-1954. (Box 19)
    - Colonial Williamsburg, 1954-1964. (Box 19)
    - Colonial Williamsburg, 1965-1968. (Box 19)
    - Correspondence of William J. Van Schreeven (Special topics), 1939-1960. (Box 17)
    - Correspondence of William J. Van Schreeven (Special topics), 1947, 1966-1969. (Box 17)
    - Correspondence of William J. Van Schreeven (Special topics), 1947-1968. (Box 17)
    - Correspondence of William J. Van Schreeven - Archives Manual, 1953-1959. (Box 17)
    - Don't Lose Your Town's History, 1947. (Box 18)
    - Draft - Virginia's Historical Records, undated. (Box 18)
    - Filing Arrangement of the Archives Division, Virginia State Library, 1948. (Box 18)
    - Historic Alexandria Foundation, 1964-1965. (Box 18)
    - Relation of Local Historical Societies to the Field of Research, 1956. (Box 18)
    - Review of Essay on the Government of the English Plantations, 1946. (Box 18)
    - Review of The History and Present State of Virginia, 1947. (Box 18)